‎NETFLIX 出品
‎你覺得我打偏了嗎
You think I missed?
‎瞧…
Well…
‎打偏了10厘米
Off by four inches. …for the generator.
‎嘿 你干什么 這些是我要買的
Hey, what do you think you're doin'? I wanted those.
‎好的 盧
Gotcha, Lou.
‎…還有所謂的支付贖金
…and alleged ransom payments.
‎我們過去沒有 ‎我重復一遍 沒有通過武器交易
We did not, repeat, did not trade weapons
‎或其他方式來交換人質 ‎將來也不會這樣做
or anything else for hostages, nor will we.
‎里根總統談及與伊朗的緊張關系
President Reagan addressing the heightened tensions with Iran in the country's 1953 coup.
‎嘿 盧
-Hey, Lou.
‎其他新聞 羅杰斯委員會的報告
In other news, pages from the Rogers Commission's report
‎調查了太空穿梭機挑戰者號災難 ‎讓美國宇航局備受抨擊…
on the Space Shuttle Challenger disaster, with NASA under fire…
‎你為大風暴做好準備了嗎
You, uh, ready for the big storm?
‎我要提款
Makin' a withdrawal.
‎今天要取多少錢
And, uh, how much will you be taking out today?
‎有多少取多少
Ah, whatever's in there.
‎哦
Oh.
‎好的
Okay.
‎…沒有伊朗的配合
Without Iran's cooperation,
‎我們無法結束波斯灣戰爭
we cannot bring an end to the Persian Gulf War.
‎沒有伊朗的…
Without Iran's…
‎那…是很大一筆錢呢
-There's a lot of money.
‎我知道啊
I know.
‎錢就是我存進去的
I'm the one who put it in there.
‎如果您想打電話 ‎請先投幣25美分 然后再撥號
If you'd like to place a call, please deposit 25 cents before dialing.
‎如需幫助 請掛斷后重新致電
If you need help, please hang up and try your call again.
‎蘭金
Rankin.
‎下午好 盧
Afternoon, Lou.
‎賈克斯心情很好嘛
Jax is in a good mood.
‎我不禁在想 ‎是不是因為打獵很刺激
Can't help but wonder if the spark of the hunt
‎所以才讓它興奮得不行
hasn't got him all worked up.
‎不太可能 現在不是打獵的季節
Unlikely. It isn't hunting season.
‎哦
Oh.
‎那鹿一定是突然冒出來的
Deer must have just bolted out of nowhere.
‎迅雷不及掩耳
Happened so fast.
‎我很高興你和賈克斯安全出來了
Well, I'm glad you and Jax came out of it okay.
‎你應該給自己買一條銅手鏈
You know, you ought to get yourself one of these copper bracelets.
‎-漂亮 ‎-我侄女在大陸給我買的
-Pretty. -My niece got it for me on the mainland.
‎其中一個裝著好夢安睡環
One of those stores, you know,
‎還有水晶之類的東西
with the dream catchers and crystals and whatnot.
‎我還笑她來著 但我對天發誓 ‎現在我的關節炎好多了
-I laughed at her. But I swear to God, I barely feel the arthritis anymore.
‎我又開始釣魚了
I'm fishin' again.
‎戴著這玩意兒小心別被雷劈了
Careful you don't get struck by lightning wearin' that thing.
‎早上好 盧
-Oh, that's right. Mornin', Lou!
‎我喜歡…
I love--
‎這是惡劣天氣預警
This is a severe weather watch.
‎西北太平洋近年來最大的一次風暴
The biggest storm the Pacific Northwest has seen in years
‎預計將于今天入夜后來襲
is expected to make landfall early this evening.
‎請各位居民盡量待在家里
Residents are encouraged to stay in their homes
‎做好準備 屆時會出現電力中斷 ‎低洼地區會有洪澇
and be prepared for downed power lines and flooding in low-lying areas.
‎開往圣胡安群島的渡輪也已暫停服務
Ferry service to the San Juan Islands has also been suspended
‎重開時間另行通知
until further notice
‎因為風暴將直接吹襲本區域
as the area is directly in the storm's path.
‎她跑哪兒去了呢 我不知道
Where could she be? I don't know.
‎她不在這棵樹下
She's not under this tree.
‎（價真五金店）
‎她不在這里
She's not over here.
‎她藏得真好啊
Oh, she's so good at hiding.
‎一定得找到她
Gotta find her.
‎也許她在里面
Maybe she's inside.
‎好 我去那里看看
Yeah, I'm gonna check there.
‎抓到你啦
-I got you! -I got you! I got you!
‎你都沒有說“小兔子”的暗號
-You didn't say the code! Little Rabbit.
‎再來一次嘛
One more time.
‎不行
-No.
‎求你了
-Please.
‎我說了不行 小薇 來吧
I said no, Vee. Come on.
‎把釘子遞給我
Pass me a nail?
‎謝謝
Thanks.
‎媽媽 你覺得 ‎爸爸會很快找到寶藏嗎
Mom, do you think Daddy's gonna find the treasure soon?
‎已經兩年了
It's been two years.
‎我不知道 小薇 他應該很快會找到的
I don't know, Vee. I bet he's real close.
‎那爸爸會回家嗎
And then is Daddy gonna come home?
‎知道嗎 風暴似乎還要過會兒才來
You know, the storm looks like it's a while away.
‎我們或許可以再玩一次躲貓貓
We could probably fit in another game.
‎我打賭你撐不過三分鐘 ‎就會被我找到了
I bet you can't make it past three minutes before I find you, though.
‎-我可以的 ‎-我覺得你撐不過
-Oh, I can. -Oh, I don't think you can.
‎好吧 我看看 準備好了嗎 預備…
All right. Let me see. Ready? Set…
‎-游戲開始 ‎-游戲開始
-Game on! -Game on!
‎一
One…
‎二
two…
‎三
three…
‎四
four…
‎五 六
five… six…
‎七…
Seven…
‎-嘿 盧 ‎-房租 明天
-Hey, Lou. -Rent. Tomorrow.
‎我知道 聽我說 ‎我得為風暴準備食品物資
I know. Listen, now, I had to lay in supplies for the storm.
‎-能不能… ‎-不能延期
-So I was wondering whether-- -No extensions.
‎好吧
-All right.
‎明天 把錢放在里面桌子上
-Tomorrow. Inside. On the table.
‎-不然放在信箱里會弄濕的 ‎-錢會付給你的
It'll get wet in the mailbox. You'll get it.
‎小薇
Vee!
‎你這人是怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
‎明知道附近有小孩 ‎你為什么還要開這么快
Why you gotta drive so goddamn fast? You know there's a child nearby.
‎這世界不是游樂場 ‎教你的孩子要自己小心
World's not a playground. Teach your kid to look out for herself.
‎來吧 賈克斯
Come on, Jax.
‎-嘿 ‎-進去吧
-Hey. -Go inside.
‎-媽媽  ‎-小薇 進去吧
-No, Mom! -Vee, go inside.
‎沒事吧
-Everything o-- okay?
‎別跺腳 小姑娘
And no stomping, little girl.
‎不 不用了 謝謝你 克里斯
-No. We're fine. Thanks, Chris.
‎-你還好嗎  ‎-還好 我只是累了
-You doin' all right? -Yeah, I'm just tired.
好吧
All right.
盧還在讓你煩惱嗎
Is Lou still bein' a pain in your ass?
‎我跟你說過這事
-I told you about that?
‎是啊
-Yeah.
‎-你不記得了 我們… ‎-不記得了
Yeah, you don't… you don't remember? -No.
‎聽我說 我們當時都喝醉了
-Look, we were both pretty drunk, so…
‎-是啊 ‎-對 顯然如此
-Yeah. Yeah. -Clearly,
‎因為我都不記得我說過了
'cause I… I don't remember that.
‎我記得你使出了吃奶的勁兒 ‎在唱“宛如處女”
I do remember you singing "Like A Virgin" at the top of your lungs.
‎請你發誓不告訴別人
Oh, please swear you'll never tell.
‎不然呢
Or what?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎不然…
Or, uh…
‎媽 我找不到河馬先生
Mom! I can't find Mr. Hippo!
‎我得走了
Listen, I gotta go.
‎嘿 你有沒有…
Hey, have you, um…
‎媽 幫我找把它找出來
-Mom, help me find him.
‎你找機會跟小薇談過了嗎
Have you had a chance to talk to Vee yet?
‎關于她爸的事
About her dad?
‎你沒事吧
You all right?
‎-我能搭個便車嗎  ‎-當然可以 上車吧
-Any way I could get a ride? -Yeah, of course. Get in here. -Thank you.
‎倒霉的租賃車壞掉了 ‎你真是幫了我一個大忙
Sorry about that. Oh, damn rental car broke down on me. You're a lifesaver.
‎天啊 我把你的座位都弄濕了
Oh, jeez, I'm-- I'm gettin' your seat all soaked.
‎別擔心 得虧是我開車經過看見了你
Don't worry about it, man. I'm just glad I passed you when I did.
‎風暴天會很危險
The storm's gonna be gnarly.
‎（《論死亡與臨終》）
‎好深奧啊
Heavy reading.
‎對 給我一個朋友買的
Yeah, I bought it for a friend of mine.
‎她的前夫三個月前去世了 ‎她很難接受現實 所以…
Her ex died three months ago, and she's just-- she's havin' a hard time facin' it.
‎明白了 你想幫她面對現實吧
I see. And you wanna help her face it, right? Hm?
‎-因為你想比做朋友更進一步  ‎-不 聽我說 我只是…她有個孩子
'Cause you wanna be more than just friends? Oh, look, I just-- She has a kid.
‎她想慢慢來
She wants to take it slow.
‎哦 我喜歡這個樂隊
Oh! I love this band.
‎-杰夫波卡羅是個很厲害的人 ‎-哦 是的 他是最棒的
Oh, Jeff Porcaro's the man. -Oh, yeah. He's the best.
‎搞什么 操
Fuck! What the fuck?
‎（大學資金）
‎（爸爸 小薇）
‎小薇
Vee…
‎小薇 看著我
Vee, look at me.
‎你之前問過爸爸的事 對吧
You know when you were asking about Daddy earlier?
‎怎么說呢…
Well, um…
‎寶貝 他…
Baby, he, um…
‎他很愛你
He loves you so much.
‎他心里一直在掛念你
And he thinks about you all the time.
‎你在做什么呢
What are we making?
‎-友誼手鏈 ‎-哦
-Friendship bracelets. -Oh.
‎我想做一條友誼手鏈
I wanna make a friendship bracelet.
‎這個是給盧的
This one is for Lou.
‎你在給盧做手鏈 為什么
You're making a bracelet for Lou? Why?
‎我喜歡盧
I like Lou.
‎我知道你不喜歡
-I know you don't.
‎不 我喜歡啊
-Yeah, I do.
‎好吧 我其實不喜歡盧 ‎但是你為什么喜歡她呢
Okay. I actually don't like Lou. But why do you like her?
‎因為賈克斯喜歡她 而我喜歡賈克斯
Well, Jax likes her, and I like Jax.
‎哦
Oh.
‎我向來不是話多的人 ‎我就長話短說了
"I've never been one for many words, so I'll keep this short."
‎房子歸你了 拿去賣掉吧
"The house is yours. Sell it."
‎冰箱的肉夠賈克斯吃一個月 ‎還有給你一些現金
"There's a month's worth of meat for Jax in the freezer, and some cash for you."
‎我做的一些決定 你永遠都不會理解
"There are certain decisions I made that you will never understand."
‎但那都是過去的事了
"But that's all in the past now."
‎人生可能會很殘酷
"Life can be cruel."
‎有些事我很擅長 ‎但有些事我做得一塌糊涂
"What made me great at some things made me lousy at others."
‎我希望我能說 ‎自己的所作所為帶來了好的結果
"I wish I could say that some good came from what I did."
‎事實上
"In truth,
‎我讓世界變成了更危險的地方
I left the world a more dangerous place."
‎現在該睡啦 好了
-Bedtime, now!
‎-河馬先生  ‎-我累壞了
-Mr. Hippo! -I'm exhausted.
‎來吧 河馬先生 晚安
Come on, Mr. Hippo. -Good night.
‎我好熱
-I'm hot.
‎我也很熱 ‎但很快就涼快了 因為下雨了
Yeah, now I'm hot too. But you'll be cold soon because it's raining.
‎只是風而已 寶貝 別害怕
Oh, it's just the wind, baby. Don't be scared.
‎我沒有怕
-I'm not scared.
‎-好的 ‎-你害怕嗎
-Okay. -Are you scared?
‎-你今晚想跟我睡嗎  ‎-如果你想 我就跟你睡
-Do you wanna sleep with me tonight? -Oh, if you need me to, I will.
‎我想讓你跟我睡
-I think I do.
‎該死
Oh shit.
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
‎小薇
-Vee…
‎-說話注意點 ‎-該死
-Watch your mouth. -Shit!
‎我要去把斷電器打上去
I'm just gonna go flip the breaker.
‎我馬上回來 好嗎
I'll be right back, okay?
‎媽媽
Mommy?
‎是你嗎
Is that you?
‎克里斯
Chris!
‎小薇
Oh! Vee!
‎不 小薇
No! Vee!
‎小薇
Vee!
Vee! Vee! Vee! Vee? Vee!
‎-電話呢  ‎-搞什么鬼
-Where's your phone? -What the hell?
‎該死的電話在哪 我得打給警長
Where's your goddamn phone? I gotta call the sheriff.
‎-媽的 操  ‎-別急 出什么事了
-God damn it! Fuck! -Slow down. What happened?
‎小薇不見了
-Vee's gone.
‎你又讓她跑開了 她走不了多遠
-What, you let her wander off again? -She's not gonna get far in this.
‎不 她爸爸把她帶走了
-No, no, no. -Her father took her.
‎她爸爸
-Her father?
‎他來了 他怎么會在這里
He's… he's here. How the hell is he here?
‎等等 你看到他了嗎
Hold on. You saw him?
‎沒有 我…
No. I…
‎他應該是死了 但是他找到了我們
He… he's supposed to be dead, but he found us.
‎我以為擺脫他了
I-- I thought we were free of him.
‎他還殺了克里斯
-He killed Chris.
‎天啊
-Jesus Christ.
‎你的鑰匙呢  ‎車子發動不了 我得去找警長
Where are your keys? The car won't start. I gotta get to the sheriff.
‎-我來開車 ‎-好
-I'll drive. -Okay.
‎糟了
Hm.
‎快點
-No, no, no, no, no! Come on!
‎-怎么了  ‎-快跑
-What's wrong? -Run!
‎怎么了
What?
‎趴下
Down!
‎你怎么知道會爆炸
Ho-- how did you know it was gonna blow up?
‎炸彈就是會爆炸
Bombs tend to.
抱歉 伙計
Sorry about that, buddy.
結果我還沒做完
Turns out I'm not done yet.
‎炸彈 盧 ‎這說明他一直在計劃這件事
A bomb? It means he's been plannin' this, Lou.
‎我們需要更多支援 我們得去找警長
We gotta get more help. We need to get to the sheriff.
‎沒法去找他 沒有車 電話也壞了
Can't get to him. No cars. Phones are down.
‎我們在城外十幾公里
We're ten miles outside of town.
‎每耽誤一秒 ‎你孩子就走遠一步 我得去追蹤他們
Your kid's gettin' further away by the second. I have to track 'em.
‎什么
What?
‎你追蹤他們
Track 'em? You?
‎去拿電池 在廚房
Get batteries. Kitchen.
‎你不了解情況 菲利普以前當過兵
You don't understand. Philip was a Green Beret.
‎他在中美洲做了可怕的事 ‎因此還被通緝了
Wanted for some terrible shit that he did in Central America.
‎是戰爭罪什么的
War crimes kind of shit.
‎我看了法庭手稿 他折磨俘虜來作樂
I saw the court transcripts. He was torturing hostages for fun.
‎他訓練有素
He's highly trained.
‎是個炸彈專家 ‎媽的 我們可不是他的對手
An explosives expert. Well, we're no match for him, Lou.
‎我們需要專業的救援 ‎光憑你和你家狗是不行的
We need professional help. You and the dog ain't gonna cut it.
‎他從你的拖車里拿走了什么嗎
Did he take anything from your trailer?
‎拿走了小薇最喜歡的 ‎河馬先生玩偶 還有一條毯子
Her-- her favorite stuffy, Mr. Hippo. -And a-- a blanket.
‎他想讓她舒服一點
-He wants her comfortable.
‎他只想讓她保持安靜
He wants her quiet.
‎正在翻修
Renovations.
‎警察試圖逮捕他時 ‎他炸毀了自己的公寓
When they tried to arrest him, he blew his apartment up.
‎警察也發了死亡證明 ‎他怎么可能還活著
They sent a death certificate. How the hell could he still be alive?
‎氟烷 會讓人昏睡的氣體
Halothane. Sleeping gas.
‎你沒被迷暈 算你走運
You're lucky it didn't knock you out.
‎他用東西把她拉著走了
He's pullin' her in somethin'.
‎他要是想帶小薇離開島 ‎事情就更復雜了
If he gets her off the island, this will get a lot messier.
‎飛機場和渡輪都關了
Airport and ferry are closed.
‎要坐私人游艇 他就得去海岸
Private vessel. He's headed to the coast.
‎他有領先優勢 ‎我得抓緊了 你待在這里
He's got a head start. I gotta move fast. Stay here.
暴風雨過后  再進城
The storm clears, head into town.
當你看到第一個房子時 就打電話給警長
First house you see, call the sheriff.
‎-喂 你要去哪里  ‎-去找我的孩子
-Hey, where are you goin'? -To find my child.
‎你不知道自己在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
‎如果你拖慢我的速度 ‎我就把你扔下不管
If you slow me down, I will leave you behind.
‎賈克斯 繼續走
Jax. Right on.
‎什么都看不到
You can't see shit.
‎我們很接近了 正在穿過山脊
We're close. We're clearing the ridge.
‎我們馬上就到
We'll be there shortly.
‎該死的一群白癡
-Fuckin' idiots.
‎不 沒關系
No. No, no, no. It's okay.
‎我知道好久沒見了
I know it's been a while.
‎也許這能喚起你的記憶
Maybe this'll jog your memory.
‎這個是教堂
Here's the church…
‎這是尖頂
Here's the steeple…
‎把它打開 然后是…
Open it up and…
‎是你
It's you.
‎對 是的 是我
Yes, it is. It's-- it's me.
‎是我 寶貝
It's me, sweetie.
‎你探完險回來了
You came back from your adventure.
‎沒錯
I sure did.
‎我還給你帶了禮物呢
And… and I even brought you a present.
‎是在寶藏堆里找到的嗎
Is it part of the treasure?
‎寶藏 對
Uh, treasure? Yeah!
‎沒錯 當然是了
Yeah, it sure is.
‎而且你和我要一起 ‎去一趟屬于我們的探險
And… you and I are gonna go on our own adventure together.
‎媽媽在哪兒 她跟我們一起去嗎
Where's Mo-- Where's Mommy? Is she coming with us?
‎對 她當然要去
Yeah, of course she is. Of course she is.
‎我給她留了紙條和提示 讓她跟上來
I left her a note and some clues to follow us,
‎她晚點會跟我們匯合的 好嗎
and she's gonna meet up with us after, okay?
‎別急嘛
Uh-- Whoa.
‎你要說什么
What do you say?
‎謝謝 爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
‎好的
-Okay.
‎能收到嗎
- Do you copy?
‎收到 快上線 能聽到嗎
Come on. Get on radio. -Do you copy?
‎好吧 我還有一件事要處理
-All right, I've gotta do one more thing.
‎然后你就要和我一起開始探險了
And then you and I are gonna start our adventure together.
‎所以你戴上這個 好了 就是這樣
See, you put these on… All right, like that.
‎好嗎
Okay?
‎給你
Here.
‎你看到什么了嗎
You see anything?
‎-你認識他們  ‎-托尼和格里 是菲利普的戰友
-You know them? -Tony and Gerry. They served with Philip.
‎-他們就跟菲利普一樣狠毒 ‎-來吧
They're just as vicious as he is. Come on.
‎趴下別動 你的外套就是一個活靶子
Stay down. Your jacket might as well have a target painted on it.
‎我們等著
-We wait.
‎萬一這只是聲東擊西呢
Suppose this is just a distraction?
‎好爭取更多時間讓他帶著小薇離開 ‎他就喜歡搞這種鬼把戲
Buying him more time to get away with Vee. It's the kind of game he likes to play.
‎拿閃亮的東西在你面前晃
Danglin' somethin' shiny in front of you,
‎然后他趁你不備 給你腦袋一悶棍
and you don't notice when he's about to bash you over your goddamn head.
‎你會用槍嗎
Do you know how to use this?
‎我會 我離開他之后去上課學過
Mmm, yeah. -I took lessons after I left him.
‎好的 我得去看一下
-All right, I'm gonna go have a look.
‎如果有人離得太近 就用這個
If anybody gets too close, use this.
‎直接戳眼睛 眼瞎的人沒法要你的命
Go for the eyes. A man can't kill what he can't see.
‎-你在哪里學的這些東西  ‎-女童子軍
-How do you know all this? -Girl Scouts.
‎賈克斯 待著別動
Jax. Stay.
‎這種鬼天氣 沒人想跟著他過來
All right, no one's gonna follow him in this shit.
‎感覺這又是一次菲利普的蹩腳游戲
I'm telling you, this feels like another one of Philip's fucked-up games.
‎有人嗎
Hello?
‎不好意思 我把這里都轉了個遍
Oh, excuse me. I'm completely turned around out here. I--
‎我在找我家的狗 可憐的小家伙…
I… I was looking for my dog. The poor little guy--
‎-我沒看到狗 ‎-好吧
I haven't seen any dogs. Okay.
‎你有電話可以借給我用嗎 我只想…
Do… do you have a phone I could use? -I just want--
‎就你一個人
-Are you alone?
‎很不幸 是的
Unfortunately. Um…
‎聽我說 我感覺自己 ‎沒法再撐三個小時走路回家了
Look, I-- I don't think I can make it the three hours back home, but…
‎不過 要是能歇歇腳就好了
if I could just rest and get my… my bearings?
‎天啊
Christ.
‎好吧 只能待兩分鐘
-Okay. Just two minutes.
‎非常感謝
Thank you so much.
‎該死
Oh shit.
‎多謝你的善心
Oh, bless your heart.
‎早上好啊
Oh, good morning.
‎她的狗跑丟了 被雨淋濕了
She lost her dog, man. She's soaked.
‎只要讓我的血液循環起來就好
Just need to get my blood movin' again.
‎天啊 外面的風暴真是厲害
My goodness. Quite a storm out there.
‎你叫什么名字
What's your name?
‎哦 抱歉 我叫瑪莎
Oh, sorry, I'm-- I'm Martha.
‎弗萊明
Flemming.
‎但你們可能認識我丈夫 ‎他上班的地方在…
But you might know my husband, Gordon. -He works at the--
‎不認識
-I don't.
‎來 坐一下吧
Here. Why don't you grab a seat?
‎-讓冰冷的腳休息一下 ‎-那就太好了
-Give those cold feet a break. -They sure could use it.
‎謝謝
Thank you.
‎非常感謝
Thank you so much.
‎你在島上待了很久嗎
So… been on this island long?
‎32年了
-Oh, 32 years.
‎不知道這有什么好的
-I don't get the appeal.
‎過來一趟也麻煩 天氣又糟糕
It's a pain in the ass to get to. -Weather's shit.
‎得慢慢習慣才行
It's an acquired taste.
‎我就很喜歡這里
I love it, though.
‎我倒覺得是個藏身的好地方
-Good place to hide, I reckon.
‎得了吧 托尼 放松點 她只是個老太
Come on, Tony, relax. She's just an old lady.
‎（來自德黑蘭的愛）
‎這湯聞著好香啊
The soup smells so good.
‎這里真舒服 又暖和
So nice and warm in here.
‎那一定是我家賈克斯
That must be my Jax.
‎坐下 瑪莎
Sit down, Martha.
‎他要帶她去哪里
Where is he taking her?
‎快說
Where…
‎他要帶她去哪里
…is he taking her?
‎老鷹灣
Eagle Bay.
‎然后呢
And then where?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎我發誓 我只知道這些
I swear. That's all I know.
‎你要開槍打我嗎
You gonna shoot me?
‎事態
Things, uh…
‎更嚴峻了
escalated.
‎賈克斯 我是怎么跟你說的
Jax. What'd I tell you about that?
‎在你殺格里之前 ‎他說了關于小薇的線索嗎
Gerry, he say anything about Vee before you killed him?
‎一個字都沒說
Not a word.
‎給你 把這個拿出去 仔細翻一下
Here. Take this outside. Go through it.
‎喂 拜托
Hello? Come on!
把那個東西關掉
Turn that thing off.
‎-我們也許能聯系到警長 ‎-這種天氣就別指望了
-We might be able to reach the sheriff. -Not in this weather.
‎更有可能會引起菲利普的注意
More likely it'll tip off Philip.
‎-哪個頻道才是… ‎-別跟我爭辯 快放下
-What channel would the emergency-- -Don't argue with me. Leave it.
‎難以置信
Unbelievable.
‎你知道 我也參加過女童子軍
You know, I was in the Girl Scouts, too.
‎我拿到了射箭徽章 ‎交到了筆友 學會了急救
Got my archery badge, pen pal, first aid.
‎但是他們沒教過徒手搏擊 ‎或者拿家用物品來殺人
There wasn't one for hand-to-hand combat or murder with household objects.
‎是嗎 那肯定是我服役的時候學的
Really? Must've just been my troop, then.
‎你隸屬哪支部隊
What branch of the military were you in?
‎中情局
CIA.
‎做了26年的外勤
26 years in the field.
‎間諜
A spy?
‎-還真沒想到 ‎-要是被你猜到 我這特務就太菜了
-Wouldn't have guessed that. -Be a shit spy if you did.
‎來吧 賈克斯
-Come on, Jax.
‎爸爸
-Daddy?
‎我在呢
-Yeah!
‎我要尿尿
I need to pee.
‎你能忍一忍嗎
-Can-- can you hold it?
‎忍不住了
-Nuh-uh.
‎好吧
-Okay.
‎稍微歇一會兒
Short break.
‎有人嗎
-Hello?
‎見鬼
Damn it.
‎喂 有人在嗎
Hello, hello. Is anyone there?
‎我們快走
Let's go!
‎好了 快點 小薇
Okay, come on, Vee.
‎小薇
Vee?
Vee!
‎讓我看看
Let me see?
‎是的 它的翅膀受傷了 小薇
Yeah. No, he's got-- he's got a bad wing, Vee.
‎對
Yeah.
‎你要知道
You know…
‎有時候在大自然里
sometimes, in nature, when a…
‎當一個生物受傷了
creature's damaged…
‎其實你也救不了它
there's nothing you can do to save them.
‎就好像它注定要死亡
It's almost like they were meant to die.
‎但也許它只是累了
But maybe he's just tired.
‎也許吧 是的
Maybe. Yeah.
‎來 我把它放到這上面
Uh… Here. We'll put him right up here.
‎-好了 來吧 ‎-等等 我還沒尿尿呢
-All right. Come on. -Wait, I haven't peed yet.
‎快點 小薇 得走了
Come on, Vee. Now!
‎媽的
Fuck!
‎-操 ‎-哪里疼
-Fuck. -What's hurtin'?
‎不疼
Nothin'.
‎快點 我們得繼續走
Come on. We gotta keep movin'.
‎媽的 開什么玩笑 見鬼 我操
-Fucking kidding me! Damn it. Fuck!
‎嗨 得下來自己走了 好嗎
Hi. We have to walk now, okay?
‎-我需要休息一下 ‎-啊
-I need a break. -Huh?
‎我需要休息 暖暖身子
I need a break to warm up.
‎沒時間了 盧
No time, Lou.
‎他也會休息 ‎從他留下的蹤跡就看得出來 來吧
He takes breaks too. I can tell by the tracks. Come on.
‎該死
Oh, God damn it!
‎可惡
Oh shit.
‎我不覺得太冷
I'm not too cold.
‎你呢
You?
‎該死
Shit.
‎你帶傷走了這么久 早該告訴我才對
You walked a long way on that. You should've said somethin'.
‎好讓你拋下我不管
And give you an excuse to abandon me?
‎-那是給我的嗎  ‎-不是
Is that for me? No.
‎能給我一點嗎
Well, can I have some?
‎謝謝
Thanks.
‎你卻還是留下了
And yet you stayed.
‎你早就該做點什么了
Well, should've done somethin'.
‎是啊
Yeah.
‎謝謝你 盧 你這番話很有幫助
Thanks, Lou. That's… very helpful.
‎我是說你應該早點離開他
Just saying you could've left him sooner.
‎你知道跟他這樣的人 ‎在一起是怎樣的嗎
What is it you know about being with someone like him?
‎所以或許不要當事后諸葛
So maybe don't tell me what I should have done.
‎我都不認得跟他在一起時的自己
I didn't recognize who I was with him.
‎其實 我以為我可以治愈他
I actually felt I could fix him.
‎你知道 我們最初認識時 他很愛我
You know, when we met, he was loving,
‎他很在乎我 但他的心支離破碎
he was caring… But so broken.
‎過去這么久了 ‎我還以為都是我一個人的錯
For so long, I thought… thought it was all me.
‎我以為…
I thought…
‎為什么我會讓他失望
"Why am I failing him?
‎為什么我的愛還不夠
Why isn't my love enough?"
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎那個混蛋是個怪物
That son of a bitch is a monster.
‎不管是什么煉獄把他折磨成這副模樣
Whatever the hell made him this way.
‎反正就算用盡全世界的愛
There ain't no amount of love in this entire world
‎都沒法拯救他這種人
that's gonna be able to save that man.
‎他傷害過小薇嗎
He ever hurt Vee?
‎沒有
No.
‎還沒有
Not yet.
‎每當他大發脾氣的時候
When he would get into his moods,
‎我就跟小薇小聲說：“游戲開始”
I'd whisper to her, "Game on,"
‎然后她就會跑去躲起來
and she'd run and hide.
‎我居然把它變成了一個該死的游戲
Actually made it into a… a goddamn game.
‎你說這有多可悲
How pathetic is that?
‎他總是說 如果我帶走小薇 ‎他就會殺了我們兩個
He always said, if I took Vee away, he'd kill us both.
‎所以你說吧 我當時該怎么辦
Go on… Tell me what I should've done.
‎我想我倆都經歷了別人無法理解的事
I guess we've all been through things other people will never understand.
‎漢娜
Hannah?
‎我們會把她救回來的
We'll get her back.
‎來吧
Come on.
‎該死
Oh, shit, shit, shit, shit.
‎慢慢來 保持平穩
-Slow and steady.
‎回家吧 賈克斯
Home, Jax.
‎不準跟我爭辯 回家 快去
No arguments. Home. Now!
‎見鬼
Oh shit.
‎他到底是怎么帶著小薇一起過去的
How the hell did he do this with Vee?
‎-得爬過去才行 ‎-該死
Gotta climb around it. Oh shit.
‎哇
-Whoa!
‎來吧
Come on!
‎我扶著你
I got you.
‎很好
Good job.
‎該死
Shit.
‎天啊
Jesus.
‎真會挑時候 媽的
Not now. God damn it.
‎-盧 你怎么了  ‎-沒什么
-Lou, what's the matter? -Nothing.
‎盧
-Lou!
Lou!
‎謝天謝地
-Oh, thank God.
‎你讓我扶你起來就好了嘛
I can help you if you just let me.
‎不需要你幫我
I don't need your help.
‎媽的
-Oh, fuck!
‎起來 耽誤了一小時 得追上他
Get up. We just lost an hour on him.
‎喂 我叫你不要帶上這玩意兒
Hey, I told you to leave that behind.
‎風暴過去了 ‎我要爬上那個山頂 試著連接
Storm's passed. I'm gonna climb up to that hilltop. -Try to connect.
‎沒時間了
-There's no time.
‎見鬼 你別那么固執好嗎  ‎我們需要幫助
God damn it. Can you stop bein' so stubborn? We need help.
‎沒人能幫我們 ‎我是你的唯一希望 現在繼續走吧
-There is no one who can help us. -Shit. -I'm all you've got. Now keep movin'.
‎-你為什么要幫我 盧  ‎-老鷹灣就在前面
-Why are you helpin' me, Lou? -Huh? -Eagle Bay's just ahead.
‎-別拖慢我的速度 ‎-見鬼
-Don't slow me down. -God damn it.
我們錯過了
We missed them.
‎海浪這么洶涌 人員無法進出
No one's comin' or goin' in water this rough.
‎那他打算怎么辦
-Then what's his plan?
‎這邊
-Over here.
‎小薇
-Vee!
Vee!
‎漢娜
Hannah.
‎-你把她帶到哪里去了  ‎-別喊了
-Where did you take her? -Stop.
‎他這是在捉弄你
-He's fucking with you.
‎我們可以就這樣耗一天
We can do this all day.
‎也許你說得對 ‎我們可能確實需要幫助
Maybe you're right. Maybe we do need help.
‎你回到山里去
Go back to that hill.
‎看看你能不能聯系上蘭金 ‎緊急服務在第16頻道
See if you can raise Rankin. Emergency services are channel 16.
‎聯系到了之后回來這里跟我匯合
Meet me back here when you're done.
‎謝謝你
Thank you.
‎你打算怎么辦
What are you gonna do?
我需要休息
I need to rest.
快去
Go on.
‎嘿 等一下
Hey, hold up.
‎可別一槍崩了自己的腦袋
Try not to blow your brains out.
‎（永遠和你在一起 ）
‎（你照亮我的生活）
‎好了
There we are.
‎凍結在時間里
Frozen in time.
‎永遠和你在一起
Together forever.
‎還想再印一個嗎
Wanna do another one?
‎你知道嗎
Did you know…
‎世界各地的山洞里都有像這樣的手印
that there are handprints like these in caves all over the world?
‎等你和媽媽還有我都死了很久之后
And long after you and Mommy and I are all dead…
‎這些手印還會在這里
these handprints are still gonna be here.
‎有人嗎
Hello?
‎喂 有人能聽到嗎
Hello? Can anyone hear me? Hello?
‎有人聽到嗎
Can anybody hear me?
‎喂
Hello?
‎你好 有人嗎
Hello, anybody?
-該死 -我是蘭金‎警長
-God damn it. -This is Sheriff Rankin.
你是誰 結束
Who is this? Over.
‎警長 蘭金警長
Sheriff! Sheriff Rankin.
這是--這是漢娜·道森
This is-- this is Hannah Dawson.
‎-…被綁架了 ‎-綁架
…kidnapped. Kidnapped?
漢娜 你能聽到我說話嗎
Hannah, can you hear me?
請重復一遍好嗎
Can you repeat that, please?
好的
Uh-- Okay.
我女兒被她父親綁架了
My daughter was kidnapped by her father.
我...
I'm…
‎-盧阿德爾和我在一起 ‎-漢娜 你能確認情況嗎
Lou Adell is with me… Hannah, can you please confirm?
‎-漢娜道森 你能聽到嗎  ‎-什么
Hannah Dawson? Can you hear me? What?
‎你再說一次好嗎
Say that… say that again?
‎拜托
-Come on, come on, come on.
‎警長
Sheriff?
‎該死 好吧
Oh fuck. Okay…
‎可惡
Shit.
‎呼叫托瑞斯
Torres, come in.
‎-警長 請講 ‎-聽著 我們有情況
-Go, Sheriff. -Listen, we got a situation.
‎聽起來難以置信
This is gonna sound a bit crazy,
‎但是我想漢娜道森的女兒 ‎被她父親綁架了
but I think Hannah Dawson's daughter has been kidnapped by… by her father.
‎什么
What?
‎聽著 我們馬上把信息發布出去
Listen, let's put it on the wire, right away,
‎以防女孩被帶離這座島
in case she's taken off the island.
‎好吧 漢娜道森 薇道森和盧阿德爾 ‎她好像也提到了盧
Okay? Hannah and Vee Dawson and Lou Adell. I think she mentioned Lou.
‎放下槍
The guns.
‎慢點
Slowly.
‎你好 菲利普
Hello, Philip.
‎別擔心她
Don't worry about her.
‎我已經確保她會保持昏睡
I've made sure she'll sleep through this.
‎告訴我一件事 老實回答
Just tell me one thing. And be honest here.
‎你為什么要出賣我
Why'd you sell me out?
‎我知道你遲早會找到漢娜和小薇
I knew you'd track down Hannah and Vee sooner or later.
‎我無法永遠保護她們
I wasn't gonna be able to protect them forever.
‎保護她們 這一切都是因你而起
Protect them? All of this is happening because of you.
‎不是嗎 漢娜可能太天真了 ‎她沒想明白 但是我不傻
Okay? And Hannah may be too naive to-- to see it, but I don't.
‎漢娜不知道我是誰
Hannah doesn't know who I am.
‎你連承認我是你兒子都還做不到
You still can't even admit I'm your son.
‎菲利普 你打算做什么  ‎為什么要這樣你追我趕
So what's the plan, Philip? Why the elaborate chase?
‎為什么要讓我們追蹤你  ‎你并不想傷害你的孩子
Why let us track you? You don't wanna hurt your kid.
‎你知道嗎 那些人把我擄走時 ‎我年紀就跟小薇一樣
Did you know that Vee is the same age as I was when those-- those men took me?
‎是的 但他們就沒有 ‎像我現在這樣 對她這么溫柔了
Yeah, but they weren't as nice as, uh… as I'm being to her.
‎這樣的相似程度 你不覺得很巧嗎
Can you appreciate that? The symmetry of that?
‎我以為我媽媽也會回來救我
I thought my mommy was comin' back to save me, too.
‎那是個陷阱 ‎要是我來救你的話 我倆都會被抓
It was a trap. If I'd tried to save you, they would have had us both.
‎胡說 你只想保護自己的臥底身份
Bullshit. You wanted to maintain your cover.
‎我只是你執行任務的一枚棋子而已
I was a pawn for your mission. Nothin' else.
‎我救了你 我把你從伊朗救了出來
-I had you rescued. I got you out of Iran.
‎那你怎么不跟我一起回來  ‎原因很簡單
-Then why didn't you come back with me? Here's why.
‎因為你他媽的選擇了中情局 ‎而不是選擇自己的孩子
Because you chose the fucking CIA over your own child.
‎后來事情怎么樣
Yeah, how'd that work out for you? Hmm?
‎伊朗被你們搞得一團糟 ‎你們還做過比這更糟糕的事嗎
I mean, did you guys fuck up anything worse than you fucked up Iran?
‎然后 你偷走了我的妻子和孩子…
And then you steal my wife and-- and my kid--
‎她們跟我犯的錯無關 別牽扯上她們
Hannah and Vee had nothing to do with my mistakes. Leave them out of this.
‎你就別給我上思想道德課了
Oh, spare me the fuckin' morality lesson.
‎你早就放棄了這個權利
You gave up that right a long time ago.
‎現在還不遲
It's not too late.
‎你敢動一下 我就給你一槍
You move, I'mma put a bullet in you.
‎現在還不遲
It's not too late.
‎把小薇留給我 然后你走吧
Leave Vee with me and go.
‎我會把她們從你的蹤跡中抹去
I'll throw them off your trail.
‎菲利普 聽我說
Philip, listen to me.
‎你說得對
You're right.
‎你小時候我沒保護好你 ‎現在就讓我做彌補吧
I didn't protect you when you were a kid. So let me do it now.
‎閉嘴
Shut up.
‎怎么 你想殺我
What, you wanna kill me?
‎動手吧
Do it.
‎你昨晚帶走小薇時 ‎我正拿著來復槍抵著自己腦袋
Before I knew you took Vee last night, I had my rifle pressed against my head.
‎我不怕死
I'm not afraid to go.
‎你別總是打亂我的思緒 好嗎
You just can't stop messin' with my head, can't you?
‎我甚至不知道從何講起
Kid, I wouldn't even know where to start.
‎我知道你把自己炸死了之后 ‎我就知道時機到了
The minute I heard you blew yourself up, I knew it was time.
‎我以為漢娜和小薇會很安全 ‎我的任務已經完成了
I thought Hannah and Vee were safe. My mission was complete.
‎但你欺騙了我
But you tricked me there, didn't you?
‎你向來都比我聰明
You always were smarter than me.
‎你五歲時下象棋就比我厲害很多
Beat my ass at chess when you were five years old.
‎記得嗎
Remember that?
‎我記得
I do.
‎哦 菲利普
Oh, Philip.
‎你猜怎么著
You know what?
‎這次要按我的游戲規則來玩
For once, we're playin' my game.
‎是時候做個了結了
It's time to end this legacy.
‎好讓這一家子都擺脫痛苦
Put this whole family out of its misery.
‎菲利普 你是她爸爸
Philip, you're her father.
‎你也是我媽媽啊
And you're my mother.
‎媽媽
Mom! Mom!
‎我們會在燈塔等你
We'll be waiting for you at the lighthouse.
‎一定要帶漢娜一起來
Make sure you bring Hannah.
‎別讓我們久等
Don't take too long.
‎媽的
Fuck.
‎只是想問問你情況怎么樣
Just checking in on ya. How are you doing out there?
‎副警長 進展如何
-Talk to me, Deputy.
‎在全境通緝布告里沒找到匹配
-Still no hits on the APBs.
‎已把卡車上的炸彈告知了交通運輸部 ‎跟驗尸官匯報了尸體情況
I notified ATF about the bomb in the truck and the coroner about the body.
‎等天氣好轉 他們就會派隊伍過來
They're sending teams when the weather lets up.
‎奧卡斯島警察局
Orcas Island Sheriff's Department.
‎是的 長官
Yes, sir.
‎警長 是聯邦執法官
Sheriff, it's the federal marshals.
‎我是蘭金 你是哪位
-This is Rankin. Who's this?
‎警長 我是多米尼克科朗 ‎你收到傳真了嗎
-Sheriff, Dominick Crown here. Did you receive our facsimile transmission?
‎收到了 我正拿在手里
Yeah, I got it right here.
‎我們在全境通緝布告里 ‎看到了你們所說的盧阿德爾
We've seen the APB for the woman you know as Lou Adell.
‎她跟照片里的這個人相匹配嗎
Is she a match for the person in that photo?
‎對 是啊 看起來像是她
Yeah. Yeah, it sure looks like her.
‎-你能確信是她嗎 警長  ‎-就是她
-How confident are you, Sheriff? It's her.
‎那第二個人呢
-And the second individual?
‎等一下
-Hang on one second.
‎你認得他嗎
Do you recognize him?
‎不認得 你是說這家伙也牽涉其中
No. Are you telling me that this guy is involved?
‎你知道這些人所處的位置嗎
Do you have any intel on the location of these individuals?
‎-他們是不是在一起  ‎-我不知道
-Are they together? Well, I don't know if they're together.
‎我想他們要去老鷹灣 位于島的西側
What I believe is that they're headed to Eagle Bay, on the west side of our island.
‎我們必須確保沒有平民前往那附近
We need to make sure no civilians go anywhere near that location.
‎設置路障 封鎖該區域
Set up roadblocks and cordon the area.
‎還有個被綁架的小女孩 ‎她媽媽也在那里
There's a kidnapped girl and her mother out there.
‎-你等一會兒 ‎-什么
-Hold. -Excuse me?
‎這混蛋居然讓我等著 難以置信
Asshole put me on hold. Unbelievable.
太他媽不可思議了
Un-fuckin'-believable.
蘭金警長
Sheriff Rankin?
‎對 就是我
- Yeah, right here.
‎那個男性逃犯是美國特種部隊的
The male fugitive is US Army Special Forces,
‎因多起謀殺平民案而被定罪
convicted in the murder of numerous civilians.
‎那個女性是中情局的重點通緝目標
The female is a high-priority target for the CIA.
‎中情局 盧阿德爾
The CIA? Lou Adell?
‎這項調查現在由美國執法官負責
This investigation is now under the jurisdiction of the US Marshals.
‎已獲授權使用致命武力
Lethal force has been authorized.
‎禁止任何人進入老鷹灣 ‎你們部門的人不準…
Do not allow any approach to Eagle Bay. -Not by your department, not--
那里有一個被綁架的女孩和她的母親
There-- there is a kidnapped girl and her mother out there.
‎別干擾我們執行任務 警長
Stay out of our way, Sheriff.
‎（急救箱）
‎盧 抱歉 我來晚了
Lou, sorry it took me so long.
‎我試著盡量往高處爬 但是…
I tried to get as high as I could, but…
‎天啊 見鬼
-Jesus. Oh shit.
‎天啊 好 等等 我來幫你
Oh God, oh God, oh God. Okay, wait, wait. Let me help. Let me help.
‎是他干的嗎
-Did he do this?
‎小薇呢 她沒事吧
And Vee? Is she… is she all right?
‎她暫時沒事 他把她帶去燈塔了
She's okay for now. He's taking her to the lighthouse.
‎動作要快
Do it quick--
‎我正在弄
-I'm trying.
‎盡量用紗布填滿它
Fill it with gauze. As-- as much as you can.
‎-該死 ‎-來吧 深入一點 把傷口包緊了
-Oh shit. -Come on, deeper. -Really pack it in.
‎我正在弄 天啊 盧 ‎很抱歉 我把你拉下這趟渾水
-I'm trying. -Jesus, Lou. -I'm so sorry I dragged you into this.
‎把手放在這里 用力按 我去拿些膠布
Put your hand here. Right. Press down. Okay, good. I gotta-- I gotta grab some tape.
‎你聯系上警長了嗎
Hannah. Did you reach the sheriff?
‎-我也不確定 ‎-先別管了
-Uh, I don't know. -Leave it.
‎-等等 ‎-不用了
-Wait, uh-- -It's fine.
‎是我在小屋里找到的 ‎我原本想告訴你的
I found those at the cabin. I meant to tell you.
‎你在說謊
You're lying.
‎（嗨 媽媽 輪到我啦）
‎這個留言不是給我的 對吧
This message isn't for me, is it?
‎都不是給我的
None of them are.
‎你說吧
Say it.
‎我要你親口說出來
I need you to say it.
‎說啊
Say it!
‎他是我兒子
He's… my son.
‎我之前駐扎在伊朗
When I was stationed in Iran,
‎當時我必須接近一個極度危險的人物
I had to get close to a very dangerous man.
‎關系很親密
-Very close.
‎不是吧
No, no, no, no.
‎我留著孩子是為了掩護我的臥底身份
I kept the baby to keep my cover.
‎你是說菲利普嗎  ‎你的孩子 你是說你的兒子
You mean… you mean Philip? The baby? You mean your son?
‎所以是怎么回事 在玩游戲
So what is this? Some game?
‎你在捉弄我嗎  ‎怎么 是你告訴他我們在這里的嗎
You fucking with me? What, you tell him where we were, or… -
‎-不是 ‎-那是什么
-No. What-- what is this?
‎我不是在幫他
I wasn't helping him.
‎-我在幫你和小薇 ‎-別再騙我了
-I was helping you. You and Vee. -Stop lying to me.
‎快他媽的告訴我真相
-Tell me the goddamn truth!
‎是我引你到這座島上來的
I got you to this island.
‎你大學的老朋友
Your old friend from college?
‎那個人告訴你奧卡斯島 ‎是個漂亮的世外桃源 房租又便宜
The one who told you about the beautiful secluded place on Orcas Island with the cheap rent?
‎是我讓她在街上假裝偶遇你的
I had her run into you on the street.
‎我原本想阻止菲利普
I tried to stop him.
‎于是我勒索中情局 ‎逼他們調查菲利普在薩爾瓦多的行為
I blackmailed the CIA to force an investigation into what he did in El Salvador.
‎你以為是你救了我們
-You think you saved us?
‎我知道他最終會追蹤到你
-I knew he'd track you eventually.
‎你沒有救我們
You didn't save us.
‎是我帶著小薇離開了他
I got Vee away from him.
‎我每天都照顧她 確保她的安全
I took care of her every goddamn day and made sure she was safe.
‎就因為你 現在害小薇落在了他手上
Now she's out there with him because of you.
‎你根本不是英雄  ‎你他媽的是個膽小鬼
You're no damn hero. You're a fucking coward.
‎-這… ‎-那個男人的所有憤怒
-Wow. -All that rage that that man felt.
‎他心里燃燒的全部怒火
All the rage inside of that man that he felt,
‎撒在我身上的怒氣 ‎全都是你一手造成的
that he aimed towards me, is because of you.
‎不是每個人都適合當母親
Not everybody is meant to be a mother.
‎是啊 也許吧
Yeah, maybe not.
‎但你原本可以更有人性
But you could have been a little more human.
‎你每天都開車經過我們的拖車
You drove past our trailer every day.
‎盧 你開車經過自己的孫女
You drove past your own granddaughter, Lou.
‎你都沒跟她說話 ‎你一句話都沒跟她說過
You didn't talk to her. You didn't speak to her.
‎你連看都沒看她一眼
You didn't look at her.
‎什么樣的人才會這樣對待自己家人
What kind of person could do that to their own family?
‎拜托 我們得繼續走了
Come on. We gotta keep moving.
‎再也沒有“我們”了
There ain't no more "we."
‎漢娜 你不知道他們要去哪里
Hannah, you don't know where they're going.
‎你說了去燈塔 我會沿著海岸走過去
You said the lighthouse. I'll follow the coastline.
‎不要獨自過去 這是陷阱
Not on your own. It's a trap.
‎求你了 至少這件事是我在行的
-Please. There's one thing I'm good for.
‎恐怕不是了
-Not anymore.
‎你只會拖慢我的速度
You'll just slow me down.
‎賈克斯
-Jax.
‎盧
-Lou!
‎你沒事吧
Are you okay?
‎沒想過見到你居然會覺得高興
Never thought I'd be excited to see you.
‎凡事都有第一次 漢娜在哪兒
-First time for everything. -Where's Hannah?
在去燈塔的路上
On her way to the lighthouse.
‎她的女兒呢
And her daughter?
‎已經在那里了
-Already there with the… -Okay.
‎跟綁匪在一起
…the kidnapper.
‎他有武器
He's armed.
‎非常危險
Very dangerous.
‎聯邦調查局也是這樣描述你的
That's exactly what the feds said about you.
‎你留在這里 ‎等道路暢通之后 我會派人來救你
You stay here. I'll send someone for you as soon as the road's clear.
‎等等 天啊 先救我出去 ‎我在這里快喘不過氣了
Wait. For fuck's sake, help me outside. I'm suffocating in here.
‎來吧
-Come on.
‎我來扶你
I got this.
‎盧 你要告訴我 ‎為什么中情局要找你嗎
You gonna tell me why the CIA's lookin' for you, Lou?
‎我用了手里掌握的一些證據
I used some evidence I held onto.
‎什么證據
-What kind of evidence?
‎證明中情局參與了伊朗政變的文件
Documents. Proving CIA involvement in the coup in Iran.
‎我明白為什么他們很生氣了 ‎盧 他們正在趕過來
I can see why they'd be pissed about that. -Lou, they're on their way.
‎見鬼 他們可不在乎殃及無辜
Fuck, they won't care about collateral damage.
‎你得把漢娜和小薇救出去
You gotta get Hannah and Vee out of there.
‎這傷口又崩開了 我會失血過多的
This thing starts up again, I'm gonna bleed out.
‎你能去拿急救箱嗎 我落在里面了
Will you get the first-aid kit? I left it in there.
‎好
Okay.
‎盧
Lou! Lou!
‎開什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
‎盧
Lou!
‎媽媽
Mommy!
‎-媽媽  ‎-小薇
-Mommy! -Vee!
‎快來 求你了 快來
-Come! Please, come!
‎-小薇  ‎-我在這里 媽媽
-Vee! -I'm here, Mama!
‎-在上面  ‎-我來了
-Up here! -I'm coming!
‎寶貝
Baby?
‎媽媽
-Mommy!
‎嗨 媽媽
Hi, Mommy.
‎嗨 寶貝
Hi, baby.
‎我們還擔心你不會出現呢 對吧
We were afraid you weren't gonna show up. Weren't we, Vee?
‎你沒事吧
You okay?
‎她當然沒事 她和她爸爸在一起
Of course she's okay. She's with her daddy.
‎過來抱抱媽媽
Come, give Mommy a hug.
‎嘿 盧怎么樣了 她過來了嗎
Hey, how's-- how's Lou doin'? Is she-- Is she on her way?
‎天啊 瞧瞧我
Jesus, look at me.
‎這么多年了 我還在等我媽媽回來
Still waitin' for my mommy to come back after all these years, huh?
‎但我們確實需要等她來 了結這件事
But we do need her here to finish this.
‎我想給媽媽一個擁抱
I wanna give Mommy a hug.
‎菲利普 拜托
Philip, please.
‎求你了 爸爸
Please, Daddy?
‎好的 小薇
Okay, Vee.
‎反正我們也在等盧 那就抱一下吧
One quick hug while we wait for Lou.
‎我好想你啊
Oh, I missed you so much.
‎游戲開始
Game on.
‎爸爸 我能去洗手間嗎
Daddy, may I go to the bathroom?
‎當然可以 小薇
Of course you can, Vee.
‎但是上完就立刻回來 好嗎
But hey… Come right back, okay?
‎哇 盧對你的影響真不小嘛
Wow, Lou is really rubbin' off on you.
‎來 把槍給我 ‎我們都知道你不會開槍打我的
Come on, just give me the gun. We both know you're not gonna shoot me.
‎你不了解我 菲利普
You don't know me, Phil.
‎-你從來都不了解 ‎-是嗎
You never did. No?
‎如果你要開槍打我 幾年前就動手了
I know that if you were gonna shoot me, you would have done it years ago.
‎我知道你跟我和盧不一樣
I know that you're not like Lou and me.
‎你不是這種人
You're not.
‎換作是她 早就開槍了
Yeah, 'cause she would've shot me already.
‎來吧 把槍給我
Come on. Give me the gun.
‎你拋棄了我
You abandon me,
‎偷走了我的孩子 現在還開槍打我
and then you steal my baby from me, and now you shoot me?
‎你的話對我無效  ‎我不會再上你的當了 菲利普
That shit won't work on me. Not gonna work on me anymore, Phil.
‎我已經不怕你了
I'm not afraid of you anymore.
‎我不會讓你像傷害我一樣傷害我女兒
And I won't let you hurt my little girl the way you hurt me.
‎漢娜
-Hannah!
‎你還記得嗎
Do you remember?
Do you remember…
‎感覺如何
how it felt?
‎小薇 我們得跑了
Vee! We have to run!
‎小薇
Vee!
‎該死
Oh shit.
‎小薇
Vee?
‎游戲結束了 好嗎 來 小兔子
Game's over, okay? Come here, Little Rabbit.
‎我們現在就得走了
We gotta go right now.
‎他有沒有傷害你 他沒傷害你吧
Did he hurt you? He didn't hurt you, right?
‎躲起來
Oh! Hide. Hide. Hide.
‎盧
Lou.
‎-漢娜 ‎-快來
-Hannah. -Come on.
‎我們得走了
-We need to move.
‎小薇
-Vee?
‎-我的槍 ‎-弄丟了
-My gun. -Lost it.
‎-刀呢  ‎-插到菲利普的手上了
-Knife? -Stuck in Philip's hand.
‎試試從艙口出去 快去
Try that hatch. Go, go, now.
‎等等 你的外套卡住了
-Wait, your jacket's stuck.
‎該死
-Oh fuck.
‎把你推上去
Push you up.
‎你得跑到海灘盡頭 有多快就跑多快
Run to the end of the beach. Run as fast as you can.
‎-別離開我 ‎-我會來找你 我們爬不出去
-No! -I'll meet you there. -Don't leave me.
‎現在快跑 去吧 小兔子 快跑
We won't fit. You gotta run now. Go, go, go, go. Run, Little Rabbit! Run!
‎都混在一起了 沒法拆彈
It's rigged. I can't defuse it.
‎如果改變頻道 或許能爭取一點時間
Could buy us some time if I can change the frequency.
‎你要去哪里
-Wait. Where are you going?
‎咱倆當中有個真正的女童子軍
One of us was actually a Girl Scout.
‎你還帶著對講機嗎
-Do you still have the radio? -Yeah.
‎也許終于能派上用場 去把艙口踹開
Maybe we can use it after all. Go bust that gate open.
‎盧
Lou?
‎我們都在這兒
We're all here.
‎我一直希望我們可以一起做這件事
I was hoping that we could all do this together.
‎面對面
-Face to face!
‎好讓大家都以恰當的方式做個了結
So that we could end this… the right way.
‎以恰當的方式做個了結
End this right.
‎全家人一起
As a family.
‎整個家庭
‎但有時候你無法一切如愿
But sometimes, you don't get what you want.
‎該死
Fuck!
‎媽的 見鬼
‎操
-Fuck!
‎你他媽的讓我進去
Fuck! You fuckin' let me in!
‎該死
Oh shit.
‎-該死 ‎-什么
-Oh shit. -What?
‎中情局出動了
-The CIA's on the hunt.
‎他們來找菲利普還是找你
They comin' for Philip or you?
‎我和菲利普都別想活著出去
They won't want either one of us to leave here alive.
‎去吧
-Go, go.
‎-不 我只會拖慢你的速度 ‎-我不能把你撇下
-No. -I'll just slow you down. -I'm not gonna leave you here.
‎盧 去把你的孫女 ‎帶到安全的地方 我會追上來的
Lou, go get your granddaughter to safety. I'll catch up.
‎該死
Fuck!
‎小薇
Vee…
‎過來
Come here.
‎哦
Oof!
‎你是個勇敢的小女孩 你知道嗎
You're a brave little girl. You know that?
‎幫幫我好嗎
Good. Help me up, will you?
‎好 聽我說
Okay, listen to me.
‎我要你去找一根木棍 好嗎
I want you to go grab a stick, okay?
‎盡量找一根最長的 去吧
The longest one you can find. Go, go, go.
‎-媽媽  ‎-嘿 寶貝
-Mommy! -Hey, baby.
‎漢娜 對講機
Hannah. The radio.
‎在我的口袋里
In my pocket.
‎-來吧 ‎-幫幫我
-Come on. -Help me.
‎快 快走
-All right. -Come on, go, run.
‎漢娜 盡量把它舉高點
Hannah, hold this up as high as you can.
‎-你是在求救嗎  ‎-對
-Are you calling for help? -Yeah.
‎是的 這應該能引起他們的注意
Yeah. That ought to get their attention.
‎你趕緊走
You gotta go.
‎沿著這條路往鎮上走 把賈克斯帶上
Take the road back towards town.
- 把賈克斯帶來 - 你…你和我們一起來
-Bring Jax with you. -You… you come with us.
‎漢娜你要照料好你的孩子
Hannah, you take care of your kid…
‎而我會照料我的孩子
I'll take care of mine.
‎我在家給你留了封信 一定要找到它
I left a letter for you at my house. Make sure you find it.
‎走吧 小薇
Okay. Go on, Vee.
‎可惡
Oh, God damn it.
‎盧 你可別死了
Don't die on me now, Lou.
‎你眼前的就是最重要的一切
Everything that matters is right here in front of you.
‎我知道
I know.
‎去吧 快點
Go. Now!
‎對不起 孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
‎-嘿 小薇 ‎-嘿
-Hey, Vee. -Hey.
‎你好 賈克斯
Hello, Jax.
‎嘿 你現在有兩條手鏈了
Hey, you got two bracelets now.
‎對
Yeah.
‎就像你一樣
Just like you.
‎（盧）
‎一條是為了紀念朋友
One's for a friend.
‎她突然就把這房子給了你和你女兒
So, out of the blue, she just leaves you and your daughter this house?
‎是的 這間房子還有很多冷凍鹿肉
Yeah, this house and a ton of frozen deer meat.
‎門沒鎖
It's open.
‎-嘿 漢娜 ‎-嘿
-Hey, Han. -Hey.
‎你們好
Oh, hello.
‎我們還有幾個問題要問道森女士
We had a few more questions for Ms. Dawson here.
希望我沒有打擾你
I hope I'm not interrupting.
‎漢娜 驗尸官那邊有個問題
Hannah, uh, coroner's got an issue.
‎你是親屬 需要你簽名 ‎才能給菲利普的遺體放行
You're next of kin. He needs a signature to release Philip's body for burial.
‎抱歉
-Yeah. Sorry.
‎道森女士 盧阿德爾跟你提起過
Ms. Dawson, did Lou Adell ever mention
‎她在中情局任職期間的文件嗎
anything about documents from her time in the CIA to you?
‎要是提起過 她這特務就太菜了
She'd be a pretty shit spy if she did.
‎如果你想起任何線索…
If you think of anything…
‎你上次和上上次來的時候給過名片了
You gave me a card last time you were here, and the time before that.
‎任何線索都行
Anything at all.
‎好吧
All right.
‎-警長 告辭 ‎-很高興又見到你
-Sheriff. -Good to see you again.
‎別管他們
-Forget them.
‎看來你們倆準備好去西雅圖了
Looks like you two are ready for Seattle.
‎你都收拾好了
Yeah, you're all packed up.
‎對 差不多
Yeah, almost.
‎我想告訴你 追悼會辦得很體面
I wanted to tell you, you just did a beautiful job with the memorial service.
打住  不  是你干的
-Stop. -No, you did.
我想盧會很感激的
And I think Lou would have really appreciated it.
‎得了吧 那些真情吐露只會讓她作嘔
Come on now. All that sincere emotion would have made her puke.
‎她這人吧…
Oh, well…
‎她確實很有個性
-She was her own person.
‎我是說 有時候我很生她的氣 但是
I mean, sometimes, I'm just so damn mad at her, and then…
‎有時候又很想念她
Other times I miss her.
‎對家人的感情不都是這樣的嗎
Isn't that just how it is with family?
‎我向來不是話多的人 ‎我就長話短說了
"I've never been one for many words, so I'll keep this short."
‎房子歸你了 拿去賣掉吧
"The house is yours. Sell it."
‎冰箱的肉夠賈克斯吃一個月 ‎還有給你一些現金
"There's a month's worth of meat for Jax in the freezer, and some cash for you."
‎人生沒有二次機會 ‎但有時候它允許你重新開始
"Life doesn't give you second chances, but sometimes it does offer a fresh start."
‎漢娜 你會好奇我為什么這么做 ‎為什么把這一切留給你
"Hannah, you're going to wonder why I did it." "Why I left this all for you."
‎簡單來說
"The simple answer is,
‎你留給這個世界的東西 ‎會比我留下的東西更美好
you'll leave the world a better place than I did."
‎字幕翻譯：楊宇航